KALISARAN K

Contact No: 8220006890 E-Mail: kalisarankml@gmail.com

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Web Development

Domain expertise entails Health care & Higher Education Platform Application

PROFILE SUMMARY

A result-oriented professional with **2 years'** experience in user-friendly web application development in the Healthcare domain, over **1 year** experience in the Higher Education platform. Insightful knowledge GIT, MVC. Delivered applications across PHP, Bootstrap, Java Script, JQuery.

EMPLOYMENT DETAILS

March 2022 - Present PHP Developer with Ulektz Learning Solutions Pvt Ltd - Chennai, Tamilnadu.

Involved in developing and maintaining Academia and industry connect based applications

Key Result Areas:

- Communicating with the team to complete the work at correct time and guiding them to complete the work on time and
 update the status to the testing team.
- Debugged many modules.
- Wrote quality codes to program complete applications.
- Tested programs and databases to identify issues and make necessary modifications.

Dec 2018 to July 2020 - PHP Developer & Server Administrator with Concent Solutions Pvt Ltd - Hyd, Telangana.

Involved in developing and maintaining health care based applications. Pivotal in Development of Web

Key Result Areas:

- Worked closely with Project Managers and other developers to define parameters and plan detailed specifications with clear project deliverable and timeline to meet strict deadlines.
- Mentored junior developers to coach on industry best practices and techniques, resulting in competent developers and greater client satisfaction
- Performed troubleshooting of technical issues within the production environment.
- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for websites based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages

PHP, Java Script, AJAX, JQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Software & Technologies

Development Tools: CakePHP, Codeignitor, Visual Studio Code, Bit bucket, GitHub, JIRA, AWS, S3.

Database : MySQL, SQLite 3 Platforms: LINUX Administration

EDUCATION

B.E. (Computer Science and Engineering) from Kamaraj College of Engineering and Technology, in 2019.

PROJECT - 1

ULEKTZ

Website: Mar 2022 - Present - Higher Education Platform for Networking, Learning and Development.

DESCRIPTION

Web and Mobile Application for Higher Education Student and Industry Professionals to learn new technologies for update their career and connect them.

PROJECT - 2

HEALPHA

Website: Dec 2018 - Sep 2020 - Developing and maintaining Digital Medical Records of Person.

DESCRIPTION

Web and Mobile Application for School children and Out Patients to maintain their Health Records in cloud platform (AWS).

HYPERLINK's

https://ulektz.com/ https://healpha.com/

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 11.01.1998

Father's Name: S. Kalidoss

Mother's Name: K. Amutha

Address: 15 c, Arumuganagar, Kalugumalai-628552, Tuticorin, Tamilnadu.

Mother Tongue: Tamil

Nationality: Indian

Languages known: English, Tamil

Declaration

I do hereby declare that the particulars of information and facts stated herein above are true, correct and complete to the best of my knowledge and belief.